Joseph Costa Papers
Joseph Costa Papers
- Subject files
  - National Press Photographers Association (N.P.P.A,)
    - Freedom of Information (F.O.I.)
      - Policies
        - Department of Justice (Box 43)
        - Political Conventions (Box 43)
        - State Department (Box 43)
        - Port of Authority (Box 43)
      - Sigma Delta Chi (Box 43)
      - Universities (Box 43)
    - General Electric (Box 43)
    - Graflex, 6 folders (Box 43)
    - Grolier Society (Box 43)
    - Haun Record (Box 43)
    - Hearst Scholarship Proposal (Box 43)
    - Hibbert Printing Company
      - Bills, 2 folders (Box 43)
      - General, 2 folders (Box 43, 44)
    - Historian-Faber
      - 1955-1962, 7 folders (Box 44)
      - Amateur Movies (Box 44)
      - Data Displays and Systems (Box 44)
      - Descriptions of N.P.P.A. (Box 44)
      - Edom's History of Press Photography (Box 44)
      - Education (Box 44)
      - Founders of N.P.P.A. (Box 44)
      - Highlights of N.P.P.A. (Box 44)
      - Ledger (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 44)
      - Newspapers (Box 44)
      - Photo List (Box 44)
      - Telephone Conference (Box 44)
      - Writings (Box 44)
    - Honorary Recognitions
      - 1948-1951, 1953-1957, 1960-1963, 1965-1967, 14 folders (Box 44)
      - Awards Banquet Invitations (Box 44)
      - C.I.A. Award (Box 44)
      - General (Box 44)
      - Prize Possibilities (Box 44)
      - Joe Rosenthal (Box 44)
      - Sprague Award Booklet (Box 44)
      - Text for Awards (Box 44)
    - I.B.M. Contracts (Box 44)
    - Individuals
      - Curt Armstrong (Box 44)
      - Ollie Atkins (Box 44)
      - Rich Clarkson (Box 45)
      - Bruce Downes (Box 45)
      - John Faber (Box 45)
      - Mark Ferree (Box 45)
      - John Hemmer (Box 45)
      - William J. Lookadoo (Box 45)
      - Don Mohler, 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Bates Raney (Box 45)
      - Don Swenson (Box 45)
      - Burt Williams (Box 45)
      - Arthur Witman (Box 45)
    - Industrial Marketing (Box 45)
    - Insurance, 1951; 1955-1967; 15 folders (Box 45)
    - Inter-professional Activities
      - General (Box 45)
      - C.H. Morris, 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Kansas Association of Plaintiffs Attorneys (Box 45)
      - National Association Claimants Compensation Attorneys (Box 45)
    - Job Placement Bureau, 1952-1966; 6 folders (Box 45)
    - Johns Mansville Corporation (Box 45)
    - Journalists' Creed (Oversize 3)
    - Lapel Pins and Appendages (Box 45)
    - Legal
      - Gambrell (Box 45)
      - Incorporation (Box 45)
    - Library (Box 45)
    - E. Leitz Newsletter (Freier) (Box 45)
    - Local Associations
      - General (Box 45)
      - Boston (Box 45)
      - California (Box 45)
      - Carolinas (Box 45)
      - Iowa (Box 46)
      - Kansas (Box 46)
      - Long Island (Box 46)
      - Michigan (Box 46)
      - New Jersey (Box 46)
      - New York (Box 46)
      - Ohio (Box 46)
      - Pennsylvania (Box 46)
      - Virginia, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - White House (Box 46)
      - Wisconsin (Box 46)
    - Master Photo Finishers and Dealers Association (Box 46)
    - Membership
      - Affiliates (Box 46)
      - Applications, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Cards and Decals (Box 46)
      - Chairman, 1952-1954; 1958-1959,; 1966; 3 folders (Box 46)
      - Charter (Box 46)
      - Drive, 1949-1952; 1959-1966; 5 folders (Box 46)
      - Dropped and Deceased, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Dues (Box 46)
      - General
        - 1951-1954, 3 folders (Box 46)
        - 1955, 1958, 1960, 4 folders (Box 47)
      - Life (Box 47)
      - Mailing List, 1951-1960; 6 folders (Box 47)
      - Post Office (Box 47)
      - Reclassification, 1956; 1960; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Requirements (Box 47)
      - Roster, 1948; 1950,; 1956-1960,; 1966; 9 folders (Box 47)
      - Services (Box 47)
      - Survey (Box 47)
      - Sustaining
        - 1952-1960, 4 folders (Box 47)
        - 1960-1966, 3 folders (Box 48)
      - Women, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1948-1966, 9 folders (Box 48)
      - A-Z, 24 folders (Box 48)
    - Name Contest (Box 48)
    - National Association of Radio and TV Broadcasters (Box 48)
    - National Editorial Association (Box 49)
    - National Newspaper Week (Box 49)
    - National Photo Gallery (Box 49)
    - Photographers' Association of America (Box 49)
    - Photographic Society of America, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Press Releases (Box 49)
    - Public Relations
      - 1947-1967, 9 folders (Box 49)
      - Football (Box 49)
    - Publications
      - Complete Book of Press Photography, 7 folders (Box 49)
      - Booklets
        - Careers in Photojournalism (Box 50)
        - What is N.P.P.A., 4 folders (Box 50)
      - National Press Photographer (Magazine)
        - Advertisers
          - Albion Photo Products, Inc. (Box 50)
          - American Speedlight, Corp. (Box 50)
          - Ansco, 2 folders (Box 50)
          - Argus Cameras, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Auricon (Box 50)
          - Charles Beseler Company (Box 50)
          - H.A. Bohm and Co. (Box 50)
          - Bright Star Battery Co. (Box 50)
          - Brown Forman Industries (Box 50)
          - Burke and James, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Burleigh Brooks and Company (Box 50)
          - Busch Precision Camera Corp. (Box 50)
          - Calumet Manufacturing Co. (Box 50)
          - Color Corp. of America (Box 50)
          - Cormac Chemical Corp. (Box 50)
          - Dupont (Box 50)
          - DuraFlash (Box 50)
          - Ethol 90 Developer (Box 50)
          - Fidelity Manufacturing Co. (Box 50)
          - Oscar Fisher Co. (Box 50)
          - Gavaert Co. of America (Box 50)
          - General Electric Co. (Box 50)
          - Gordon Instruments (Box 50)
          - Graflex Corp. (Box 50)
          - Corp. Haloid Co. (Box 50)
          - Hanimex, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Hardale Associates, 2 folders (Box 50)
          - Heiland Research, 2 folders (Box 50)
          - Ilex (Box 50)
          - Ilford, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Jantzen (Box 50)
          - Jen Products Sales Co. (Box 50)
          - Kalart (Box 50)
          - Harold Lambert (Box 50)
          - E. Leitz, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Lisco Products (Box 50)
          - Lott Manufacturing Co. (Box 50)
          - Mar-Bar, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Medo Photo Supply Corp. (Box 50)
          - Metropolitan Group (Box 50)
          - National Carbon Company (Box 50)
          - National Photocolor Corp. (Box 50)
          - Nikon Inc. (Box 50)
          - Nordic Manufacturing Co. (Box 50)
          - Paillard, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Pako (Box 50)
          - Peerless (Box 50)
          - Plymouth Products (Box 50)
          - Raymond Advertising Agency (Box 50)
          - Realist, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Saltzman, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Shappe-Walker, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Simmon Brothers, Inc. (Box 50)
          - Standard Rate and Data Service (Box 50)
          - Strobo Research (Box 51)
          - Sylvania (Box 51)
          - Time, Inc. (Box 51)
          - Transcontinental and Western Air, Inc. (Box 51)
          - Trans World Airlines (Box 51)
          - Twing and Altman, Inc. (Box 51)
          - United States Brewers Foundation (Box 51)
          - U.S. Color (Box 51)
          - U.S. Research Laboratories (Box 51)
          - Vernier Photo Supply Co. (Box 51)
          - Wabash Corp. (Box 51)
          - Willoughby (Box 51)
          - Wollensak (Box 51)
          - Carl Zeiss, Inc. (Box 51)
        - Advertising
          - Bills, 1949; 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 51)
          - General, 6 folders (Box 51)
          - Convention Issue, 1961 (Box 51)
          - Marked Copies, 1946-1951; 5 folders (Box 51)
          - Pictures (Box 51)
        - Articles
          - General, 5 folders (Box 51)
          - 1961 (Box 51)
          - Background Material
            - General (Box 51)
            - Curtis Laboratories (Box 52)
            - Excise Tax (Box 52)
            - National Broadcasting Company (Box 52)
            - Non-Affiliated Chapters (Box 52)
            - Quill Magazine, 3 folders (Box 52)
            - President's Choice (Box 52)
            - Technical (Box 52)
            - United Press International (Box 52)
        - Authors
          - Bedford (Box 52)
          - Cooper (Box 52)
          - Edom (Box 52)
          - Geraci (Box 52)
          - Hamer (Box 52)
          - Kaye (Box 52)
          - MacLellan (Box 52)
          - Muth (Box 52)
          - Reidy (Box 52)
          - Tamaska (Box 52)
          - Threlfall (Box 52)
          - Wallace (Box 52)
          - Woodson (Box 52)
        - Book Binders (Box 52)
        - Cartoons, 2 folders (Box 52)
        - Cartoons (oversize) (Oversize 4)
        - Change of Executive Editors (Box 52)
        - Engraving, 2 folders (Box 52)
        - Features
          - Book Reviews (Box 52)
          - How This Picture Was Made (Box 52)
          - TV-Newsreel Column (Box 52)
        - General
          - No date, 5 folders (Box 52, 53)
          - 1959-1960, 3 folders (Box 53)
          - 1962-1967, 6 folders (Box 53)
        - Mailing Privileges (Box 53)
        - Printers
          - Prospective, 2 folders (Box 53)
          - Burt Printing Company, 2 folders (Box 53)
          - Criterion Linotyping and Printing Co. (Box 53)
          - Periodical Press Corporation (Box 53)
          - Stuart Perkins, 4 folders (Box 53)
        - Subscriptions, 4 folders (Box 53)
    - Publicity, 4 folders (Box 54)
    - Pulitzer Awards (Box 54)
    - Radio and Television News Directors Association, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Salute to Seasons (Box 54)
    - Soap Box Derby Flag Raising Controversy (Box 54)
    - Speeches Given by Non-N.P.P.A. Members to N.P.P.A. (Box 54)
    - Standard Operating Procedure (Box 54)
    - Stationery, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Supplies, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Sylvania Electric Products, Inc. (Box 54)
    - Taxes on Photographic Equipment (Box 54)
    - Technical
      - General, 5 folders (Box 54)
      - Brochures, 5 folders (Box 54)
      - B-C Flash System (Box 54)
      - Lighting Survey (Box 54)
      - R.O.P. Color (Box 54)
      - Shutter Speeds (Box 54)
      - Silver Shortage Information (Box 55)
    - Television
      - Information (Box 55)
      - Roster (Box 55)
      - Shows Portraying Cameramen (Box 55)
    - Unemployed (Box 55)
    - Union Carbide and Carbon Corp. (Box 55)
    - U.S. Air Force (Box 55)
    - U.S. Camera, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Volunteers Service Photographers, Inc. (Box 55)
    - Working Conditions
      - Football (Box 55)
      - Survey (Box 55)
      - Vatican (Box 55)
    - World Travel Plan, Inc. (Box 55)
  - Personal
    - 1944-1966, 10 folders (Box 55)
    - Color Postcards (Box 55)
    - Honorary Tarheels (Box 55)
    - Briefcase Contents (Box 55)
- Photographs
  - Business
    - Arecibo, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Cardinal Spellman and Pope Pius XII (Box 56)
    - By Costa (Oversize 7)
    - Of Costa (Oversize 7)
    - Eye on Science Series, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Historical (Box 56)
    - New York Sunday Mirror, mounted covers (Oversize 7)
    - Publications
      - Beginner's Guide to Color Photography (Oversize 4)
  - N.P.P.A.
    - Competitions
      - American Society of Magazine Publishers' Picture Annual (Box 56)
      - Clipping Contest (Box 56)
      - Fifty Great Newspictures (Box 56)
      - Graflex (Box 56)
      - Judges (Box 56)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 56)
      - Newspictures of the Year, 1956; 1958; 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Popular Photography (Box 56)
      - Regional, 2 folders (Box 56)
      - United Press International (Box 56)
      - U.S. Camera (Box 56)
    - Conventions
      - 1948-1950, 2 folders (Box 56)
      - 1954-1956, 5 folders (Box 56)
      - 1958, 2 folders (Box 56)
      - 1959 (Box 57)
      - 1961-1965, 4 folders (Box 57)
      - Undated (Box 57)
    - Education
      - General, 7 folders (Box 57)
      - Short course, 1953; 1959 (Oversize 4)
    - F.O.I.
      See also Subject files: NPPA: FOI and Audio-visual: NPPA: FOI
      - American Bar Association (A.B.A.) Convention, 2 folders (Box 57)
      - American Society of Newspaper Editors' (A.S.N.E.) Convention (Box 58)
      - Cameras in the Courtroom (Box 58)
      - Colorado Hearings, 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Conference on Personal Finance Law, 4 folders (Box 58)
      - Criminal Capture (Box 58)
      - Courtroom (Box 58)
      - General (Box 58)
      - Long Island Lawyers (Box 58)
      - Miscellaneous (Oversize 4)
    - General (Box 58)
    - Historical (Box 58)
    - Miscellaneous, 19 folders (Box 58, 59)
    - Miscellaneous oversize (Oversize 6, 7)
    - Miss N.P.P.A., 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Political
      - Conventions (Box 59)
      - President Eisenhower (Box 59)
      - President Johnson (Box 59)
      - Vietnam War (Box 59)
    - Portraits (Box 59)
    - Prototypes for Insignia (Box 59)
    - Publications
      - Complete Book of Press Photography (Box 60)
        - Author's Portraits (Box 60)
        - Publicity (Box 60)
        - Miscellaneous (Oversize 4)
      - National Press Photographer Magazine (Oversize 5, 6)
    - N.P.P.
      - 1956-1961, 62 folders (Box 60)
      - 1961-1964, 40 folders (Box 61)
      - 1964-1967, 34 folders (Box 62)
    - Sports (Box 62)
    - Trains (Box 62)
  - Personal
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 62, 63)
    - Oversize (Oversize 8)
- Published material
  - Articles about Costa (Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Articles by Vincent S. Jones (Box 63)
    - Arts Magazines, 4 folders (Box 63)
    - Bulletins
      - Military (Oversize 10)
      - New York Sunday Mirror (Oversize 10)
    - Library of Congress Catalogue (Box 63)
    - Magazine Clippings, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Magazines
      - Popular Picture (Life, Look, etc) (Oversize 10)
      - Wisdom (Oversize 10)
    - Newsletter
      - Business, 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Kappa Alpha Mu (Box 63)
      - Photo Associations, 9 folders (Box 63, 64)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 4 folders (Box 64)
    - Pamphlets (Box 64)
    - Photography
      - Annuals, 10 folders (Box 64)
      - Exhibit Catalogue (Box 64)
      - Magazines (Box 64)
    - Technical Magazines (Box 64)
    - University Pamphlets (Box 64)
  - Page Proofs
    - National Press Photographer Magazine, June 1961 (Oversize 9)
  - Photographs by Costa
    - How to Article (Box 64)
    - New York Sunday Mirror (Oversize 10-12)
    - Newspaper Picture Pages (Box 64)
    - Photo Contest (Box 64)
    - Pictorial Living (Oversize 12)
    - Program Covers (Box 65)
    - U.S. Camera (Oversize 12)
- Writings
  - Annual Report, 1947-1954; 1956-1964; 18 folders (Box 65)
  - Articles
    - Famous Photographers Magazine (Oversize 12)
    - Mimeographed Copies, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Published, 10 folders (Box 65, 66)
    - Typescripts (Box 66)
  - Books
    - Words and Pictures (source material), 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Editor
    - N.P.P.A.
      - The Complete Book of Press Photography (Box 66)
      - Constitution, 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Pamphlets, 5 folders (Box 66)
      - N.P.P. Magazine
        - Bound Volumes, 1961; 1962 (Box 66)
        - Manuscript, 2 folders (Box 66)
        - April 1946-April, 1951 (Box 67)
        - May 1951-July 1953 (Box 68)
        - August 1953-November 1959 (Box 69)
        - December 1955-December 1958 (Box 70)
        - January 1959-April 1960 (Box 71)
        - May-September 1960 (Box 72)
        - September-December 1960 (Box 73)
        - December 1960-May 1961 (Box 74)
        - May-October 1961 (Box 75)
        - October 1961-February 1962 (Box 76)
        - February-May 1962 (Box 77)
        - May 1962-February 1963 (Box 78)
        - February-September 1963 (Box 79)
        - October 1963-September 1964 (Box 80)
        - October 1964-August 1965 (Box 81)
        - September 1965-November 1966 (Box 82)
        - December 1966-April 1967 (Box 83)
        - Assorted Extras (Box 84)
        - Editorials (Box 84)
  - Speeches
    - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 84)
- Audio-visual
  - Business
    - Famous Photographers School, record and filmstrip (Oversize 13)
  - N.P.P.A.
    - Contest
      - Filmstrip, 1957 Newspictures (Oversize 13)
    - Education
      - Lecture #3 (Oversize 13)
    - Freedom of Information (F.O.I.)
      See also Subject files: NPPA: FOI and Photographs: NPPA: FOI
      - Newsreel, Shrunk Verdict (Oversize 13)
      - Tape, Police-Press Panel (Oversize 13)
    - Unidentified
      - Movie (Oversize 13)
      - Tapes, 2 tapes (Oversize 13)